Ndidiamaka K. Siokwu

Email: ladykerrion@sky.com | Phone: 07910836488

Location: Derbyshire, England

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ndidiamaka-siokwu-67b1a6267

Github: https://github.com/ladykays

Portfolio: https://ladykays.github.io/my-react-portfolio/

SUMMARY

Highly motivated Front-End Web Developer with a background in Management Information Systems. Earned a certificate in Front-End Web Development from the edX Boot Camp. Previous experience in Wordpress and Web Testing. Innovative problem-solver with and a life-long dedication to learning. Strengths in critical thinking, teamwork, adaptability and communication.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, Wordpress, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, Bootstrap, Foundation Zurb, Node.js, NPM, Github, Netlify, Visual Studio Code, Terminal, Quality Center.

PROJECTS

Kre8tive Dev | https://github.com/ladykays/kre8tive-designs | https://kre8tivedev.co.uk/

- **Summary:** This website has been crafted to exhibit the diverse range of projects offered by my web development business. Through this platform, I have presented a collection of websites I've meticulously built utilising the versatile capabilities of WordPress. Each project featured here has been brought to life and is hosted using a web hosting service.
- **Role:** I assumed full responsibility for both conceptualising the layout and building the entire website.
- Tools/ Languages Used: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap 5.3, Google Fonts, Font Awesome

Wax & Wicks | https://github.com/ladykays/wax-and-wicks | https://jocular-empanada-77cf44.netlify.app/

- **Summary:** Collaborated with a team of four to create an online store for candle enthusiast seeking premium-grade candles. The site was deployed to Netlify
- Role: I was responsible for building the repository, establishing the file structure, designing the navbar, footer, basket, contact, and checkout components, implementing the checkout functionalities and deploying the site to Netlify. To ensure that the project was completed on time, I provided guidance and direction to the team throughout the process.
- Tools/ Languages Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Tailwind CSS, React.js, MUI

Weather Pourcast | https://github.com/ladykays/Weather-Pourcast | https://jessie93.github.io/Weather-Pourcast/

• **Summary:** Collaborated with a team of 4 to create an application that provides users with recommendations for cocktails based on the temperature in any location entered by the user.

- Responsibility: I was responsible for creating the footer, favourite page and the functionality for getting weather from the OpenWeather API, performing the "Roll Again" function. I also helped with bug fixing.
- Tools/ Languages Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Moment.js, OpenWeather API, TheCocktailDB API

Workday Scheduler | https://github.com/ladykays/work-day-scehduler | https://ladykays.github.io/work-day-scehduler/

- **Summary:** This is an app that enables a user to save events for each hour of their work day.
- Responsibility: I began with a starter code and modified the CSS, HTML files and added the functionalities to achieve the desired result.
- Tools/ Languages Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Moment.js, Bootstrap, Font Awesome

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Designer - Alfreton, Derbyshire - 2010 - Present

- Gathering requirements
- Negotiating cost
- Building custom websites based on user requirements
- Installing and building sites using Wordpress
- Installing and updating Wordpress themes and plugins

Teaching Assistant - Queenborough Primary School, Queenborough, Kent - March 2019 - Dec 2019

- Preparing learning resources
- Collaborating with other Teaching Assistants to put up displays around the school
- Dealing with behaviour issues
- Supervising children during lunch time
- Helping children during Information and Communications Technology lessons.

Web Tester - Sagesse Moisson, Ruislip, Middlesex - Jan 2008 - Oct 2008

Using Quality Center to

- Specify test requirements
- Write test plans
- · Run tests
- Log defects

EDUCATION/TRAINING

edXFront-End Web Developer Bootcamp - Nov 2022 - March 2023

OCR Level 2 Certificate in Supporting Teaching and Learning in Schools — Sept 2019

ISEB Foundation Certificate in Software Testing-2008

Covenant University — BSc (Hons) Management Information Systems 2006